# Jing Kang

Phone | 0475249407 Email | <u>kangjing178@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn | <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/jing-kang-93271b97/</u>

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced journalist and analyst working in the secondary market field for over 3 years. Competent storytelling skills and a nose for the truth as well as an excellent track record as a finance reporter and analyst in print and digital media. Excellent analytic skills in data collecting, analysing, and interpreting. Motivated team player with strong organizational and prioritization abilities. Areas of expertise include strong attention to detail, time management and communication skills.

### SKILLS

- Expertise with Excel VBA, MySQL, and Oracle PL/SQL.
- Proven skills on data analysis and programming skills, such as PowerBI service and Python.
- Illustrated presentation skills by using PowerPoint and other Office suites.
- Solid understanding of balance sheets concepts and systematical statistics knowledge.
- Strong numerical and logical thinking skills with an ability to solve complex problems.

## **EDUCATION**

#### University of Tasmania

Master of Information Technology and Systems

July. 2019- July. 2021

#### Yunnan University

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Business English

Sep. 2012- July. 2016

## WORKING EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst, Dec 2021-Current

#### Smart Waste Management Project, the University of Tasmania and TasICT

Our project is to develop a mobile application that uses artificial intelligence and photo recognition so a person can take a photo of an item with their phone to find out whether it can be recycled, wherever they are.

- Conducted quality analyzing of data model building and developing strategies with team.
- Detail-oriented, thorough, and vigilant to collect all necessary data without missing critical components using data collecting tools, such as Python and SQL.
- Efficiently used Excel, SPSS, Tableau and RapidMiner software to explore, visualize, clean, and integrate the data with detailed justification for later data model building.
- Collaborated with AI machine learning team to build, evaluate, compare, and determine the best performance machine learning model.
- Conducted data analysis using logistical model, KNN, tree classification and random forest method to identify high accuracy model and improved the accuracy (C-scores) by 30 percent.

#### Assistant Project Manager, March 2021-Current

## Technical Pool Program (TPP), the University of Tasmania and TasICT

Our project is to develop and improve the user interface and usability of the Dementia online diagnosis web application for non-medical background users to self-diagnosis or track their health situation.

• Collaborated with the project manager to facilitate project execution on a consistent basis.

- Creative in putting together projections for a variety of scenarios to assist the manager in making future decisions regarding the project's growth.
- Successfully assisting in outsourcing or building analysis and other product development strategies.
- Efficiently drafted and present the needed documents and submittals, such as the risk and security assessment report and the project brief slides.
- Competent communicator and high-quality delegated the team to present the project to the external stakeholders with a professional manner.

## Finance journalist and analyst, July 2016- April 2019 Shanghai Yicai Data Technology Company (Alibaba Owned)

- High-quality produced regular features and breaking news articles, focusing on technology, finance, and secondary market.
- Applied analytical and statistical skills to analyze and interpret the market opportunities and challenges in a timely manner.
- Skilled understanding of financial data analysis to effectively interpret findings in a way that makes sense to the readers and public investors.
- Conducted over 200 company leaders' interviews among diverse industries, and accurately captured key information and data for news story writing.
- Published over 100 articles that focused on finance and technology industry research with over 200k distribution.

# Volunteer Experience

**Volunteer of Legal Literacy, Oct** 2021- Dec 2021 **Launceston Community Legal Centre** 

As a volunteer of Legal Literacy,

- Determined nature of calls from clients and directed caller to the appropriate attorney or paralegal, or relative governmental departments under their permission.
- Assist visiting clients with special requests such as copies, directions, faxes, and scheduling appointments.
- Improved communication efficiency as primary liaison between clients, attorneys/staff, and relative departments.
- Proofread and re-write letters, forms, and other service documents under clients' permission and authorization.

# **Drop-in Technical Support**, **June** 2021- Oct 2021 **Launceston Library**

As a volunteer of Legal Literacy,

- Provided group and individual instruction for computer technology.
- Offered technical support for patrons and employees with computer software questions.
- Provided quality customer service regarding the circulation of library resources.
- Assist library visitors with special requests such as copies, directions, faxes, and online membership account register services.